Adam Keller

Senior Software Engineer

I'm a Senior Software Engineer currently consulting for Insight Digital Innovation located in Cincinnati Ohio with a focus in Accessibility, UI/UX design and Frontend development. I've been working in the industry for over 7+ years consulting with clients ranging from Fifth Third Bank to The Christ Hospital to Johnson & Johnsons

EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Engineer

Insight Digital Innovation

2015 - Present

- Lead on the creation of pattern librarys that would allow clients to documnet their brand components.
- Instituted accessibility audits for Furtune 500 companies that lead clients to become more A11Y aware.
- Designed and built reponsive web components that aligned to best practices and WCAG 2.0 guidelines.
- Established color, spacing and typoography language using modern methodoligies for use in design systems.

Frontend Developer

Clubessential

Sept 2014 - Sept 2015

- Developed the user interface with HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, jQuery.
- Maintained front end and backend maintenance of websites.
- Worked with management team to find and produce creative solutions.

UI Developer

Donor Drive

March 2013 - Sept 2014

- Led design and vision efforts alongside project managers to establish the best user experience for non-profit clients
- Built responsive web sites using Sass and Bootstrap as the main HTML/CSS framework.
- Worked with management team to find and produce creative solutions.

CONNECT

+1 614 778 6115

www.adam-keller.com

adam.keller.design@gmail.com

INDUSTRY KNOWLEDGE

UI Design

UX Design

Interaction Design

Product Design

Flexbox

CSS Grid

Wireframing

User-Centered Design

Design Systems

Accessibility

HTML5/CSS3

JavaScript

TOOLS & TECHNOLOGIES

Figma

Sketch

CSS Methodologies

Git

InVision

Abstract

Adobe Creative Cloud

Visual Studio Code

EDUCATION

Associates of Applied Business in

Advertising Art

The Modern College of Art and Design

2011 - 2013, Kettering OH